# **Travis Hewett**

Address: 5608 South Lexington Ave. Springfield, MO 65810

Phone: 417-230-5338

Email: thewett34@gmail.com

Senior Full Stack Developer with 6+ years of hands-on experience designing, developing, and implementing web applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. I focus on improving my work in and out of formal educational environments.

#### SKILLS / KEYWORDS

- **Front-end**: React.js/Redux, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Tailwind CSS, React Hooks
- **Back-end**: Node.JS, Next.js, Express, Django, .Net Frameworks, RESTful API, GraphQL, MySQL, MongoDB
- **Testing**: React-Testing-Library, Jest, Unit Tests and Integration Tests in React
- Languages : JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, JSX, Java, Python, C++,
  C#
- Deployment : AWS, Heroku, Netlify, Azure, GCP, Git, CI/CD
- Task Management : Scrum, Agile, Git, Asana

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Engineer Bass Pro Shops

Nov 2022 - Present

- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- CSS styles were developed to preserve the uniformity of all the screens throughout the application and positioning of screen objects.
- Developed the Login, Policy and Claims Screens for customers using AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Used Object Oriented Programming concepts to develop UI components that could be reused across the Web Application.

- Developed responsive applications using Bootstrap which allowed the same application to be optimized for both mobile and desktop resolutions.
- Involved designing in web pages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS, React.js, Redux, Flex, Mongo DB.
- Worked in using React JS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router, Animations, and Flux concept.
- Secured HTTP/Web Sockets requests with JWT and authorization middleware to prevent security threats
- Implemented stable React components and stand-alone functions to be added to any future pages.
- Used React JS for templating for faster compilation and developing reusable components.
- Used React-Auto complete for creating google maps location search on the web page.
- Used Web socket for publishing services for continuous Geo-location information updates to Google Maps.
- Built applications using React.JS which allowed us to render pages on both the client and server using the same code base.
- Developed various screens for the front end using React JS and used various predefined components from NPM (Node Package Manager) and Redux library.
- Using React JS to implement rich functions in various pages: form validation, crud, grid list, search, sort, pagination, multi-selection, tags-input, advanced/custom directives, authentication, unit tests, etc.
- Designed user interface screens and implemented application logic in Microsoft .NET framework using ASP.NET 3.0, C#.
- Experience in Restful web services to integrate between Server side to Client Side.
- Worked with JASMINE unit test framework to write unit tests for JavaScript code.

## Full Stack Developer

Apr 2022 - Oct 2022

### **Self Employed**

- Developed Single Page Web Application with React.js, Redux, Express.js, Node.js, REST API, and MongoDB.
- Designed responsive UI pages using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and react-bootstrap.
- Created reusable React c omponents for the application and used props for single directional data flow and used state for Class components.
- Used different Component life cycle hooks such as ComponentDidMount and ComponentDidUpdate for http request and fetch data.

- Configured global Store for the entire application and used Redux for state management.
- Developed Reducers and Actions to manage various UI events to update the State.
- Used npm (Node Package Manager) to install required dependencies such as react-redux, redux-thunk, react-bootstrap, and react-router-dom.
- Handled asynchronous actions by using react-thunk.
- Utilized BrowserRouter module to implement routing with Route, Link, and Switch.
- Installed and used Axios to handle http requests and response for the application and get the data from REST API.
- Implemented MVC architecture with React components as Views, models, and controllers in Node.js for API development.
- Implemented Authentication and Authorization by using JWT web token.
- Used Express.js to connect Node.js to Database MongoDB and wrote schema.
- Used Mongoose to write CRUD operations for retrieving and updating data.
- Used Postman to test API and used GIT as version control tool.

Participated in Agile methodology for application development and used JIRA as project management tool.

- Worked as a key member in Scrum team and also closely worked with system analysts and designers for the application.

# Full Stack Developer

Apr 2017 - Oct 2021

#### Jack Henry

- Created and maintained data warehouses and reports for production manager using SQL Server
- Enhanced and maintained a website for the company learning internal working of the shipping industry using HTML, CSS and Dreamweaver
- Dealt closely with working of order and supply software for shipping parts using Excel and crystal reports for data inventory and analysis
- Understood the dynamics of shipping and fabrication industry and first time exposure to professional industry and got opportunity to work as a team and assist in execution of projects.
- Created user-friendly and professionally organized UI's.

- Developed new process for current medical devices.
- Contributed to the design of the company's website using HTML5, CSS3,and JavaScript.
- CSS styles were developed to preserve the uniformity of all the screens throughout the application and positioning of screen objects.
- Developed lesson plans and consistent study of industry best practices
- Used Object Oriented Programming concepts to develop UI components that could be reused across the Web Application.
- Developed responsive applications using Bootstrap which allowed the same application
- Experienced in developing web-based applications using Python, Django, QT, C++, XML, CSS, JSON, HTML, DHTML, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Served as a scrum leader and participated in scrum meetings weekly using agile methodology to develop and oversee development of website features and applications

## **Lead Developer**

Apr 2014 - Sep 2016

## **Solarityc**

- Built front & back end components from the ground up using very hot tech stacks Stack: ReactJS, NodeJS, GraphQL, AWS Lambda, Webpack, Polymer, Electron
- Involved in Requirement analysis, preparing software Design document, development, debugging of Operations Management module in Strategic Billing project.
- Developed the User Interactive web pages in a professional manner by using web technologies like HTML/ HTML5, XHTML, and CSS3 as per company standards.
- Extensively used CSS LESS/SASS as pre processors which extend the properties of CSS.
- Applied optimization techniques to reduce page size and load times to enhance user experience using sprites.
- Developed user interface by using the React JS, Redux for SPA development.

Implemented React JS code to handle cross browser compatibility issues in Mozella, IE 7, 8, 9, Safari.

- Used React-Router to turn application into Single Page Application.

- Worked in using React JS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router, Animations.
- Worked on responsive design and developed a single ISOMORPHIC responsive website that could be served to desktop, Tablets and mobile users using React.js.
- Used the flickity.js for creating carousel-images.
- Developed component for UX-Library consisted of Button, Checkbox, Input, Icons, Toggle Button, Dropdown, Multi-Level Dropdown and many more.

#### **Frontend Developer**

Apr 2012 - Jan 2014

#### **Thousand Hills Vacations**

- Developed web applications with React, Redux, JavaScript/Typescript, Node and SQL.
- Integration of multiple data sources and databases into one system.
- Use Pentaho Report to develop reports, using the created scripts.
- Develop multiple SQL scripts using PostgreSQL manager.
- Web design and development, application development using HTML, JavaScript, and React.
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, jQuery and JavaScript.
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Built a top-class Single Page Application that supports dynamic content management using React, JavaScript, Redux, NextJS, GraphQL.
- Created a front end application with React and Airtable for skateboarders to quickly glance at a list of tricks, the detail of the trick and the ability to view and submit their progression to the database.
- Worked with software engineers and architects to create applications using JavaScript, React and Node for electrical motor testing equipment.
- Deployed cloud functions (written in Node/Typescript) to handle events triggered by changes in our Cloud Firestore database.
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.

#### **EDUCATION and TRAINING**

Ozarks Technical Community College | Computer Science | 2012 - 2016

Noble Work Foundation | Certificate Complete in Computer Software and Media Applications certificate | Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

Coding Dojo | Certificate completed in Software Development| Apr 2022 - Sep 2022

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

Manager for Beginners | Udemy | Issued Mar 2023 | Credential ID UC-adac3666-4a6a-492f-96e8-2ec47de8803b

Become an Effective Communicator | Udemy | Issued Dec 2022 | Credential ID UC-73030c10-b079-4bda-aab4-8c1bf87775e

The Beginners 2022 Cyber Security Awareness Training Course | Udemy | Issued Dec 2022 | Credential ID UC-341D9CD5-9F10-4333-B61A-5B946528C57A

CompTIA A+ | CompTIA | Issued Jul 2019